Hello English learners, welcome back to EnglishPod.
英语学习者你们好，欢迎回到EnglishPod。
My name is Marco.
我是Marco。
And I'm Erika.
我是Erika。
And we're bringing you a very advanced lesson today.
今天我们为大家带来一堂非常高级的课程。
That's right.
没错。
We're talking about another business topic, aren't we?
我们又在讨论一个商业话题，对吧？
It's a topic that's kind of popular these days, all about efficiency and reducing costs.
这个话题最近挺流行的，全是关于效率和降低成本。
So we're going to be talking about the just-in-time philosophy.
所以我们要讨论的是准时制理念。
I don't know much about this philosophy, so good thing we've got Marco here.
我对这个理念了解不多，还好有Marco在这里。
Well, what we are going to be looking at is not really in-depth.
嗯，我们要看的其实不是特别深入的内容。
We're just going to be looking at some basic points of what a just-in-time philosophy would
我们将要探讨准时制理念在公司中的一些基本要点。
be like in a company.
会是什么样子。
But what we're really going to be looking at is the language to do with this philosophy,
但我们真正要关注的是与这一理念相关的语言，
right?
对吧？
Exactly.
没错。
We're going to be looking at some technical terms and some other useful phrases that you
我们将学习一些专业术语和其他有用的短语，
can use when you are talking in a business setting.
在商务场合交谈时可以使用。
Okay.
好的。
Well, why don't we get started with the language then?
那么，我们开始学习语言吧？
Okay.
好的。
Let's take a look at vocabulary preview.
我们来看看词汇预览。
Vocabulary preview.
词汇预览。
On vocabulary preview today, we have the word lead time.
今天的词汇预览中，我们有单词“lead time”。
Lead time.
Lead time。
L-E-A-D, lead.
L-E-A-D，lead。
Lead time.
Lead time。
Right.
对。
Like lead.
就像“lead”一样。
This is something that factories usually would use.
这通常是工厂会用的东西。
Yeah.
是的。
I guess lead time is the time in between point A and point B on a production schedule,
我想前置时间就是生产计划中从A点到B点之间的时间，
right?
对吧？
Right.
对。
So you could have, for example, production lead time.
所以你可以有，比如，生产前置时间。
So that's the time between when you make an order and when the product is finished.
那就是从你下订单到产品完成之间的时间。
Exactly.
没错。
And you could also have delivery lead time.
你也可以有交货前置时间。
So the time between when you place an order and when the product gets delivered to you.
也就是从你下订单到产品送达你手中的时间。
So depending on the companies, you have different lead times.
所以根据公司的不同，你有不同的前置时间。
Some are three days, other are five days, other are 45 days.
有些是三天，有些是五天，有些是四十五天。
And we at EnglishPod have a two week lead time for our podcast, right?
而我们EnglishPod的播客有两周的准备时间，对吧？
But our delivery lead time is every other day.
但我们的交付周期是每隔一天。
That's true.
没错。
Nice.
不错。
Okay.
好的。
That's all we're going to be previewing today.
这就是我们今天要预览的全部内容。
So why don't we just listen to the dialogue and then we'll come back and explain some
所以我们不如先听对话，然后再回来解释一些
of these tricky vocabulary words that we'll see.
我们会看到的棘手的词汇。
I called this meeting today in order to discuss our manufacturing plan.
我今天召开这个会议是为了讨论我们的生产计划。
As I'm sure you're all aware, with the credit crunch and the global financial crisis, we're
我相信各位都清楚，由于信贷紧缩和全球金融危机，我们
obligated to look for more cost efficient ways of producing our goods.
必须寻找更具成本效益的生产方式。
We don't want to have to be looking at redundancies.
我们不想被迫裁员。
So we've outlined a brief plan to implement the just-in-time philosophy.
因此，我们制定了一个简要计划来实施准时制理念。
We have two basic points that we want to focus on.
我们有两个重点要关注。
First of all, we want to reduce our lead time.
首先，我们要缩短交货期。
Why would we want to do that?
为什么要这么做？
I think this is not an area that really needs to be worked on.
我认为这个领域并不需要改进。
Well, we want to reduce production and delivery lead times for better overall efficiency.
嗯，我们想缩短生产和交货周期，以提高整体效率。
Right.
好的。
Production lead times can be reduced by moving workstations closer together, reducing queue
生产周期可以通过将工作站靠得更近来缩短，从而减少排队时间。
length like, for example, reducing the number of jobs waiting to be processed at a given
比如，减少某个时刻等待处理的工作数量。
machine, and improving the coordination and cooperation between successive processes.
机器，并改进连续工序之间的协调与合作。
Delivery lead times can be reduced through close cooperation with suppliers, possibly
通过与供应商的紧密合作，可以缩短交货周期。
by inducing suppliers to locate closer to the factory, or working with a faster shipping
通过引导供应商将地点设在离工厂更近的地方，或者与更快的运输公司合作，
company.
公司。
I see.
我明白了。
That makes sense.
有道理。
The second point is that we want to require supplier quality assurance and implement a
第二点是，我们希望要求供应商质量保证并实施一项
zero-defects quality program.
零缺陷质量计划。
We currently have far too many errors that lead to defective items, and therefore, they
我们目前有太多导致次品的错误，所以它们
must be eliminated.
必须被消灭。
A quality control at the source program must be implemented to give workers personal responsibility
必须实施源头质量控制计划，让工人承担个人责任。
for the quality of the work they do, and the authority to stop production when something
他们所做工作的质量，以及发现问题时停止生产的权力。
goes wrong.
出问题了。
I'm with you on this one.
我支持你。
It's essential that we reduce these errors.
我们必须减少这些错误。
We've got to force our suppliers to reduce their mistakes.
我们必须迫使供应商减少错误。
Exactly.
没错。
Well, let's look at how we're going to put this plan into action.
嗯，我们来看看如何把这个计划付诸实施。
First.
第一。
Okay, so they're going to implement just in time in their company.
好的，所以他们要在公司实施准时制。
Yes.
是的。
Yeah, I guess they're putting in some cost control measures.
嗯，我猜他们正在采取一些成本控制措施。
So, Marco, there's some great language in here.
那么，Marco，这里面有一些很棒的语言点。
Why don't we look at it now in Language Takeaway?
我们何不在语言要点环节看看呢？
Language Takeaway.
语言要点。
Okay, the first word today.
好的，今天的第一个词。
Redundancies.
裁员。
So this is kind of a strange word because usually a redundancy is when you're speaking,
这个词有点奇怪，因为通常 redundancy 是指说话时，对吧？
right?
对吧？
Yeah, maybe when you say something that's already been said.
是的，可能当你说了已经说过的话。
Exactly.
没错。
You say something that has already been said, but we also use it in the business world.
你说了一些已经说过的话，但我们在商业领域也使用它。
Right, and it comes from the base word redundant, right?
对，它来自词根 redundant，对吧？
Okay.
好的。
Meaning extra, more than what's needed.
意思是多余的，超出需要的。
Okay.
好的。
So when a person or position is made redundant, basically it means they get laid off, right?
所以当一个人或职位被裁掉时，基本上意味着他们被解雇了，对吧？
Right.
对。
So redundancies are a synonym of layoffs.
所以 redundancies 是 layoffs 的同义词。
Exactly.
没错。
Okay.
好的。
All right, let's take a look at our next word.
好了，我们来看下一个词。
Workstations.
工作站。
So workstation could be anything from your desk.
工作站可以指你的办公桌。
Yeah, or maybe a workbench.
是的，或者工作台。
A workbench.
工作台。
Or even a place on a production line.
甚至是生产线上的一个位置。
Right.
对。
So you're a certain machine or something like that.
比如你操作某台机器之类的。
So basically a workstation is the area where you work.
所以基本上工作站就是你工作的区域。
Okay.
好的。
So you can say, can we get a new workstation for the new team member?
所以你可以说，我们能给新团队成员配一个新的工作站吗？
Or I could say, I want to move my workstation closer to my employees.
或者我可以说，我想把我的工作站搬得离我的员工更近一些。
All right.
好的。
So workstation.
所以是工作站。
Okay, let's take a look at our next word.
好的，我们来看看下一个词。
At a given machine.
在某个给定的机器上。
At a given.
在某个给定的。
This is an interesting way to say at any machine.
这是一种有趣的说法，意思是“在任何机器上”。
Exactly.
没错。
Okay.
好的。
So this is operating exactly the same as here, the word given is operating exactly the same
所以这里的用法和“any”完全一样，单词“given”的用法和
way as any.
“any”一样。
As any.
和“any”一样。
Yeah.
是的。
Okay.
好的。
So let's listen to some examples of how we can change it up a little bit and we can use
那么我们来听一些例子，看看我们如何稍微变换一下，使用
this given word.
这个“given”这个词。
Example one.
例子一。
In this factory, how many cars are in production at any given time?
在这家工厂，任何给定时间有多少辆汽车在生产中？
Example two.
例子二。
On any given day, about 40 million people use the internet.
在任何一天，大约有4000万人使用互联网。
Example three.
例子三。
Firefighters have to be ready to attend an emergency at any given moment.
消防员必须随时准备应对紧急情况。
All right.
好的。
So any given time, at any given moment.
所以是任何给定时间，任何给定时刻。
Yep.
嗯。
Um, any given day.
嗯，任何给定的一天。
Okay.
好的。
Now let's take a look at our last word today.
现在我们来看看今天的最后一个词。
Defective.
有缺陷的。
So if something is defective.
所以如果某样东西有缺陷。
It has a problem with it.
它就有问题。
It has a problem.
它有问题。
Yeah.
是的。
We can say defective is an adjective.
我们可以说 defective 是一个形容词。
Right.
对。
And the noun is defect.
名词是 defect。
Defect.
Defect。
Yep.
是的。
So if something has a defect, it is defective.
所以如果某物有缺陷，它就是 defective。
Right.
对。
So for example, maybe you produce chairs and you make one and this chair is missing a wheel.
比如，你生产椅子，做了一把，这把椅子少了一个轮子。
Okay.
好的。
So it's defective.
所以它是有缺陷的。
Yes.
是的。
The defect is the missing wheel.
缺陷是缺少轮子。
The defect is the missing.
缺陷是缺失。
Okay.
好的。
And before we listen to our dialog again, I want to take a look at this phrase.
在我们再次听对话之前，我想看看这个短语。
I'm with you on this one.
我在这点上同意你。
So what is that?
那么这是什么意思呢？
What does that mean exactly?
那到底是什么意思？
I'm with you on this one.
在这点上我同意你。
I agree with you.
我同意你。
I agree with you on this point.
在这一点上我同意你。
Exactly.
正是如此。
Okay.
好的。
So if you agree with somebody on a certain point, you would say, oh, I'm with you on
所以如果你在某个点上同意某人，你会说，哦，我同意你
this one.
这一点。
I agree with you.
我同意你。
Exactly.
正是如此。
Okay.
好的。
So now, let's listen to our dialog again and we'll come back and talk a little bit more
现在，让我们再听一遍对话，然后回来再聊一聊
about the history of this just in time.
关于准时制生产的历史。
I called this meeting today in order to discuss our manufacturing plan.
我今天召开这次会议是为了讨论我们的生产计划。
As I'm sure you're all aware, with the credit crunch and the global financial crisis, we're
我相信各位都知道，由于信贷紧缩和全球金融危机，我们
obligated to look for more cost-efficient ways of producing our goods.
必须寻找更具成本效益的方式来生产我们的产品。
We don't want to have to be looking at redundancies, so we've outlined a brief plan to implement
我们不想考虑裁员，因此我们制定了一个简要的计划来实施
the just-in-time philosophy.
准时制生产理念。
We have two basic points that we want to focus on.
我们有两个基本要点需要关注。
First of all, we want to reduce our lead time.
首先，我们要缩短我们的交货期。
Why would we want to do that?
我们为什么要那么做？
I think this is not an area that really needs to be walked on.
我觉得这个地方其实没必要走上去。
Well, we want to reduce production and delivery lead times for better overall efficiency.
嗯，我们想缩短生产和交付周期，以提高整体效率。
Right, production lead times can be reduced by moving workstations closer together, reducing
对，生产周期可以通过把工作站靠得更近来缩短，减少
queue length like, for example, reducing the number of jobs waiting to be processed at
例如，减少等待处理的任务数量。
a given machine, and improving the coordination and cooperation between successive processes.
一台给定的机器，以及改进连续工序之间的协调与合作。
Delivery lead times can be reduced through close cooperation with suppliers, possibly
通过与供应商的紧密合作，可以缩短交货周期。
by inducing suppliers to locate closer to the factory, or working with a faster shipping
通过引导供应商将工厂设在更近的地方，或者与更快的运输公司合作，
company.
公司。
I see.
我明白了。
That makes sense.
有道理。
The second point is that we want to require supplier quality assurance and implement a
第二点是，我们要求供应商质量保证，并实施
zero-defects quality program.
零缺陷质量计划。
We currently have far too many errors that lead to defective items, and therefore, they
目前我们因错误导致的缺陷品太多，因此
must be eliminated.
必须消除这些错误。
A quality control at the source program must be implemented to give workers personal responsibility
必须实施源头质量控制计划，让工人对
for the quality of the work they do, and the authority to stop production when something
自己的工作质量承担个人责任，并在出现问题时有权停止生产。
goes wrong.
I'm with you on this one.
我同意你的观点。
It's essential that we reduce these errors.
减少这些错误至关重要。
We've got to force our suppliers to reduce their mistakes.
我们必须迫使供应商减少错误。
Exactly.
没错。
Well, let's look at how we're going to put this plan into action.
好吧，我们来看看如何将这个计划付诸实施。
First...
首先……
All right, so Marco, I mentioned at the beginning of the lesson that I don't know much about
好的，马可，我在课程开始时提到过，我对准时制了解不多，
just-in-time, but luckily you do, right?
但幸运的是你了解，对吧？
Yeah, I know a little bit about it.
是的，我了解一点。
So tell me a little bit about where this philosophy came from.
那么请告诉我，这种理念从何而来？
What are the origins of this idea?
这个想法的起源是什么？
It actually became really popular with Toyota, and it was called the Toyota Production System.
它实际上因丰田而变得非常流行，被称为丰田生产系统。
So many people think it's Japanese, but in reality, the Japanese got it from the United
很多人以为这是日本的，但实际上，日本人是从美国学来的。
States.
美国。
It's a philosophy that was thought up by Ford Motor Company in order to improve their production
这是一种由福特汽车公司提出的哲学，旨在改进他们的生产线。
line.
生产线。
But when the Japanese visited Ford Motor Company, it wasn't fully implemented yet, and oddly
但当日本人参观福特汽车公司时，这套方法还没有完全实施，而奇怪的是，
enough, they found this philosophy working already in a piggly-wiggly.
他们发现这种哲学已经在Piggly-Wiggly超市中发挥作用了。
What's a piggly-wiggly?
什么是Piggly-Wiggly？
Piggly-wiggly was a chain of grocery stores in the United States.
Piggly-Wiggly是美国的一家连锁杂货店。
I'm not sure if they're still around, but yeah, they were really big, and basically
我不确定现在是否还存在，但当时它们规模很大，基本上
piggly-wiggly was using this to improve their whole system of shipping and of stocking and
Piggly-Wiggly用这种方法来改进他们的整个运输和库存系统。
everything.
一切。
Okay, so how does it work?
好的，那它是怎么运作的？
So basically what you try to do is make your processes more efficient, reduce the amount
基本上你要做的就是让你的流程更高效，减少
of space you're using, et cetera.
你使用的空间等等。
And this was really important for Japanese because, of course, they don't have that much
这对日本人来说非常重要，因为当然，他们没有像其他国家那样
space in Japan to have these huge warehouses like in other countries.
在日本有那么多空间来建大型仓库。
So what you're saying is they're producing goods just for the time they need it, right?
所以你的意思是他们只在需要的时候才生产商品，对吗？
Exactly.
没错。
So trying to not be overstocked or- Or have a long lead time or something.
所以尽量不库存过多，或者不有太长的交货时间之类的。
Long lead times where you have to keep something in a warehouse, exactly.
长交货时间意味着你必须把东西放在仓库里，没错。
So that's why it's so efficient.
所以这就是为什么它如此高效。
And also it's about improving the efficiency between processes.
而且这也是关于提高流程之间的效率。
So what's sometimes called a bottleneck.
这就是有时所谓的瓶颈。
You can have really good processes in the beginning, but in the end, maybe you have
你可以在开始时流程很好，但到最后，也许你只有
only one workstation that's taking all these orders and everything gets bottled up and
一个工作站处理所有订单，然后所有东西都堵住了，
it causes delays.
导致延误。
It's slow, yeah.
很慢，是的。
So in the dialogue, they want to implement the just-in-time strategy as a way of avoiding
所以在对话中，他们想实施准时制策略来避免
redundancies.
冗余。
But it sounds to me like actually this might cause redundancies sometimes.
但在我看来，这有时反而可能导致裁员。
Well, yeah, sometimes it does.
嗯，是的，有时确实如此。
Sometimes when you make workstations more efficient or when you make all your processes
有时当你让工作站更高效，或者让你所有的流程
work more fluidly, sometimes inevitably you will have to lay off some people that are
更流畅地运作时，有时不可避免地要裁掉一些
redundant.
多余的人。
Okay.
好的。
Have you ever worked in a company where they've implemented just-in-time?
你有没有在实施准时制的公司工作过？
No, actually, I've never really worked at a place where this philosophy was working,
没有，实际上，我从未真正在实施这种理念的地方工作过，
but I did used to work at a place where we had Six Sigma, which is a little bit similar.
但我确实在一个推行六西格玛的地方工作过，这有点类似。
Well, I guess we'll need a lesson on Six Sigma in the future.
嗯，我想我们以后需要上一节关于六西格玛的课。
Yeah, we'll see if we come up with Six Sigma and what it means.
是的，我们看看会不会讲到六西格玛以及它是什么意思。
It's kind of interesting, but we want to hear what you think.
这挺有趣的，但我们想听听你的想法。
Yes.
是的。
Have you guys worked in a place where they use just-in-time?
你们有没有在采用准时制的公司工作过？
Exactly.
没错。
Or if you have any quality control measures or how does your company avoid having defective
或者你们有没有什么质量控制措施，或者你们的公司如何避免有缺陷的
items or defective services?
产品或服务？
So visit our website, EnglishPod.com.
那就访问我们的网站 EnglishPod.com。
And Marco and I are always around to respond to your comments and answer your questions.
我和 Marco 随时都在，回复你们的评论并回答你们的问题。
Exactly.
没错。
So until then, it's-
那么在此之前，我们——
Goodbye.
再见。
It's a nice day.
天气真好。